<data>
	<about>
		<subsection>
			<tabName>SYNOPSIS</tabName>
			<html><![CDATA[<b>SYNOPSIS:</b>
<i>Row Hard No Excuses</i> is an award-winning documentary that chronicles the voyage of the only American entry in a rowing race across the Atlantic Ocean. It is both an exciting sports-adventure story and an intimate portrait of the two-man crew that explores masculinity, midlife and ambition.

At 51 and 41, John Zeigler and Tom Mailhot are among the oldest competitors to participate in the Atlantic Rowing Challenge, a three thousand mile race from the Canary Islands to Barbados. They spend three years and personal savings to make their dream of winning possible, but once on the water, they find the grueling crossing is easy to underestimate, and their quest offers one major obstacle after another. Drawing from their compelling video diary at sea, the film engages the audience in the emotional challenges and rewards of their arduous journey. With a camera on nearly every boat, a diverse chorus of other teams—men and women, young and old—adds context to a meditation on human endurance and perseverance in the most extreme conditions.

Directed by first time feature director Luke Wolbach, <i>Row Hard No Excuses</i> is a labor-of-love collaboration with his father, Bill Wolbach. “<i>Row Hard No Excuses</i>” is the slogan John and Tom wore on their t-shirts before the start of the race.

<b>BACKGROUND:</b>
Ocean rowing, as a sport, has only been around since the inaugural Atlantic Challenge race in 1997. Before then crossings were strictly Guinness Book of World Record affairs. In fact, fewer people have rowed across the Atlantic than have climbed Mount Everest. Race rules pit two-person teams against each other rowing unassisted with no food drops or navigational aid. The challenge is an enormous undertaking even before the start. Each team has to gain their own sponsorship, see to the building and outfitting of their boat (which arrives as a plywood kit) and leave their jobs and families for a couple of grueling months at sea. Rowers have to contend with sleep deprivation, seasickness, isolation, boredom and cramped living conditions. Most of the competitors row naked to avoid painful chafing. Even with a steep entry fee and no prize money, Tom and John’s race drew thirty-six teams from fifteen nations including New Zealand, Australia, South Africa, China, and eight European countries.
			]]></html>
		</subsection>
		<subsection>
			<tabName>CHARACTERS</tabName>
			<html><![CDATA[<b>John Zeigler</b> (Rower)
John was just a teenager when he first dreamed of rowing the Atlantic. Born and raised in New Jersey, he is the father of two girls. Every morning at 4:00 am, he and his brother, Danny, open the doors to their food wholesaling business, which he started with his father in the mid-1980s. A self-described fitness fanatic, John is a marathon canoe racer with rugged good looks and the upper body of a football player. His decision to pursue the race was the last straw that ended his marriage.

<b>Tom Mailhot</b> (Rower)
Tom, a New England native, is an ex-minor league hockey player whose career was stopped short by an eye injury. He has since become an accomplished kayak adventurer. His tall physique, unkempt blond hair and bushy moustache give him the look of a modern day pirate. He has an intense gaze that masks a mischievous sense of humor. Tom was laid off from his job as a construction supervisor for putting too much energy into building the boat and ended up deeply in debt as a result of the race. 

<b>Tori Murden</b> (Tom and John’s coach)
Tori is the first woman to row solo across the Atlantic and Tom and John’s unofficial advisor. Her successful crossing came after two failed attempts, one that was cut short by hurricane Danielle, which nearly killed her. She has written a thesis on the theology of adventure and her spiritual outlook introduces a different perspective on the race.
            ]]></html>
		</subsection>
		<subsection>
			<tabName>FILMMAKERS</tabName>
			<html><![CDATA[<b>Luke Wolbach</b> (Producer, Director, Camera, Editor)
Luke is an award-winning filmmaker and editor residing in San Francisco. His first film, <i>Seeds of Tibet: Voices of Children in Exile</i>, which he co-produced and co-directed, was a half hour documentary about the lives of young Tibetan refugees at a school in Northern India. It was broadcast by PBS affiliates throughout the country and was awarded an Earthwatch Award, a Cine Eagle Award and a documentary award at the Philadelphia International Film Festival. He has worked independently as an editor on projects that have broadcast on PBS, Bravo, and the National Geographic and Sundance channels. <i>Row Hard No Excuses</i> is his first collaboration with his father, Bill Wolbach.

<b>Bill Wolbach</b> (Executive Producer, Producer, Camera)
<i>Row Hard No Excuses</i> is Bill’s first film. In the past he has worked as tech support and as a consultant for financial institutions. More recently he turned his hobby and passion for motorcycles into a job as a BMW motorcycle technician. Active in his community, he has served on the board of directors at Boston’s South End Community Health Center for over twenty years. During his college years he rowed crew for Harvard and now gets his exercise in an ocean going single scull. It was through competitive paddling that he met Tom Mailhot and learned of the Atlantic Rowing Challenge. Though immediately drawn to the event, he decided to make this documentary rather than enter. 
            ]]></html>
		</subsection>
		<subsection>
			<tabName>CREDITS</tabName>
			<html><![CDATA[Directed by Luke Wolbach
Produced by Bill Wolbach &amp; Luke Wolbach
Edited by Traci Loth &amp; Luke Wolbach
Original Music by B. Quincy Griffin
Graphic Animation by Erik Dillinger
Executive Producer Bill Wolbach
With generous support from Lenny Lieberman

FEATURING (American)
Tom Mailhot &amp; John Zeigler
Tori Murden McClure
Danny Zeigler
Dianne Zeigler
Sarah Evertson
Lee Mailhot
Sarah Kessans
Emily Kohl

FEATURING (Other Teams)
Jonathon Gornall
Dominic Biggs
Debra Veal
Andrew Veal
Rune Larsson
Niclas Mardfelt
Pedro Ripol
Francisco Korff
Steph Brown
Jude Ellis
Gary Fooks
Dominic Marsh
Pascal Hanssen
Serge van Cleve
Damian West
Alex Hinton
Sun Haibin
Christian Havrehed
Jo Lumsdon
Tim Humfrey

CAMERA
Tom Mailhot
John Zeigler
Luke Wolbach


CO-PRODUCER
Traci Loth


PRODUCTION ADVISORS
Toby Beach
Ethan Berry
Robert Hawk
Chris Rowe
Gail Silva
Peter Yost


CONSULTING EDITORS
Eric Neudel
Kim Roberts


GRANT WRITER
Ben Wolbach


TORI MURDEN INTERVIEWER
Addie Wolbach


ADDITIONAL CAMERA
Sarah Evertson
Al Viator
Bill Wolbach

			
POST PRODUCTION SOUND SERVICES
Robert Berke Sound, San Francisco


SUPERVISING SOUND EDITOR
Mark Escott


SOUND EDITORS
Robert Berke
Stephen Berke

ONLINE FACILITY
Philo Television, San Francisco


ONLINE EDITORS
Mike Dennis
Shirley Gutierrez


FISCAL SPONSOR
Film Arts Foundation, San Francisco


FUNDED IN PART BY
Pacific Pioneer Fund


MUSICIANS
Paul Baker – vocals &amp; guitar
Bryan Bowman – drums &amp; percussion
Yair Evnine – guitar &amp; cello
Lorenzo Farrel – bass


MUSIC SUPERVISION &amp; CLEARANCE
David Wurzburg and Brooke Wentz at The Rights Workshop

"No Controles"
Written by Ignacio Cano
Performed by Cafe Tacuba
Courtesy of Universal Music Group

"Unreal"
Written by Jules Blattner and Josh Davis
Performed by UNKLE and DJ Shadow
Courtesy of Universal Music Group

"Only Burn"
Written by S. Buttrich, P. Bendtsen, H. Radeker
Performed by 18th Dye
Courtesy of 18th Dye

"Psychosis 1"
Written by Joel Cadbury, Richard File, James Lavelle, James McDonald, and Brett Shaw
Performed by UNKLE with South, Courtesy of Music Beyond
            ]]></html>
		</subsection>
		<subsection>
			<tabName>LANTERN FILMS</tabName>
			<html><![CDATA[
            
            
            ]]></html>
		</subsection>
	</about>
	
	
	<press>
		<subsection>
			<tabName>REVIEWS</tabName>
			<html><![CDATA[“Like all good sports docs, the film goes from micro to macro on a dime,
ultimately achieving an exhausted beauty.”
Ty Burr, Boston Globe

“Compelling… more deeply revealing 
than the triumph-over-adversity saga one expects.”
Dennis Harvey, Variety

“The ordeal is captured in all its gory glory...
a terrific personal epic of endurance and wit.”
Roger Moore, Orlando Sentinel

“Raw with emotions... nothing less than fascinating.”
Adia Waldburger, Park City Record

“This film is a triumph... it is a testimony to the vast loneliness of the ocean 
and the mental fortitude it takes to cross it.”
Bob Whitby, Orlando Weekly

“An engrossing, tautly edited documentary.”
Joshua Katzman, Chicago Reader

“A meditation on the outer limits of human endurance, the commitments we make to our friends and to ourselves, and what it means to be a winner… It is also imbued with a good deal of humor and beauty… a remarkable film.”
Michael Read, Release Print (San Francisco)

“A great benchmark for the genre… it’s impossible not to be swept away… This is the one you shouldn’t miss if it comes on TV or DVD. See now. No Excuses.”
Gina Carbone, Portsmouth Herald (New Hampshire)

“The film is a mix of all the classic narratives: man versus himself, man versus God, and man versus another man (in this case, his teammate). Friendships are destroyed, marriages are tested, and innumerable blisters are popped throughout the voyage, which is as psychologically challenging as it is physically brutal.“
Christian Schaeffer, The Pitch (Kansas City)

“Similar in some ways to Touching the Void (2003), Row Hard is especially effective in illustrating how extreme physical conditions can lay bare a person's true self.”
Cheryl Eddy, San Francisco Bay Guardian

“The film’s measured pace works… Row Hard delivers more than a chronicle of a tortuous competition—it explores the protagonists’ near-fanatical quest for ‘success’, and the hunger of a son for his father’s recognition.”
Laura Lewis-Barr, Screen Magazine (Chicago)

“Provides thought-provoking moments carried and remembered by the viewer
 long after the final frame has ended.”
Scott Neil, Royal Gazette (Bermuda)

“It gets at the heart of what it means to be human and why sports, or journeys, 
are an essential part of human existence.” 
Sam Petri, Planet Jackson Hole

“Row Hard is, simply put, fascinating… Keep an eye out for this one… 
because it really deserves an audience.”
John Serba, Grand Rapid Press

“Unlike Ernest Hemingway's 'Old Man and the Sea' or Yann Martel's 'The Life of Pi,' this 
event really happened. But truth always has been stranger than fiction.” 
Martha’s Vineyard Times
            ]]></html>
		</subsection>
		<subsection>
			<tabName>AWARDS</tabName>
			<html><![CDATA[<b>2007</b>
BEST DIRECTOR — Tenerife International Film Festival
MUST SEE AWARD — MountainFilm in Telluride
BEST SPORTS ACTION FILM — Jackson Hole Film Festival
BEST STORYTELLING IN A DOCUMENTARY — Nantucket Film Festival
BEST DOCUMENTARY — New Hampshire Film Festival

<b>2007</b>
BEST SPORTS ACTION FILM — Flagstaff Mountain Film Festival
BEST SPORTS FILM — Tiburon International Film Festival
            ]]></html>
		</subsection>
		<subsection>
			<tabName>PRESS KIT</tabName>
			<html><![CDATA[Download the press kit <u><a href="http://www.rowhardnoexcuses.org/RHNEPressKit.pdf" target="_blank">here</a></u>.
            ]]></html>
		</subsection>
	</press>	
	
	<screenings>
		<subsection>
			<tabName>PBS BROADCASTS</tabName>
			<html><![CDATA[We will be getting new broadcast dates every week. Please check back often.
If you'd like to see <i>Row Hard No Excuses</i> near you, contact your local PBS station to request it.


KENW Portales, NM
Wednesday, April 14, 2010 at 11am

Georgia Public Television
Friday April 16, 2010 at 10pm

KPBT 2 Odessa, TX
Sunday, April 18, 2010 at 6pm

KEDT Corpus Christi, TX
Thursday, April 22, 2010 at 8pm
Thursday, April 29, 2010 at 9pm

KNCT Killeen, TX
Thursday, April 22, 2010 at 8pm

NHPTV EXPLORE, NH
Saturday, April 24, 2010 at 8pm and 12am

KLRN 2 San Antonio, TX
Wednesday, April 28, 2010 at 9pm

WGCU Fort Myers, FL
Wednesday, April 28, 2010 at 7pm

WKAR 4 WORLD East Lansing, MI
Saturday, May 1, 2010 at 8pm

WCNY Syracuse, NY
Sunday, May 2, 2010 at 11pm

KPTS Wichita, KS
Saturday, May 8, 2010 at 10pm

KET 2 Kentucky
Sunday, May 23, 2010 at 5pm

KET Kentucky
Tuesday, May 25, 2010 at 9pm


Coming Soon: Los Angeles, New York, San Francisco, Seattle and many more.            
            ]]></html>
		</subsection>
		<subsection>
			<tabName>FESTIVALS</tabName>
			<html><![CDATA[<b>2007</b>
Slamdance Film Festival 
True/False Film Festival
Bermuda International Film Festival
Florida Film Festival
Chicago International Documentary Festival
Independent Film Festival of Boston
Tenerife International Film Festival
MountainFilm in Telluride
Jackson Hole Film Festival
Waterfront Fim Festival
Provincetown International Film Festival
Nantucket Film Festival
Calgary International Film Festival
Sidewalk Moving Picture Festival
Port Townsend Film Festival
Edmonton International Film Festival
Camden International Film Festival
New Zealand International Documentary Festival
New Hampshire Film Festival
Taos Mountain Film Festival
Temecula Valley International Film Festival
BendFilm
Detroit Docs
Hot Springs Documentary Film Festival
Santa Fe Film Festival
Anchorage International Film Festival

<b>2008</b>
Wild and Scenic Environmental Film Festival
Spokane International Film Festival
San Francisco IndieFest
Boulder International Film Festival
Big Sky Documentary Film Festival
Sedona International Film Festival
Flagstaff Mountain Film Festival
Pacific Palisades Film Festival
Los Angeles United Film Festival
Tiburon International Film Festival
East Lansing Film Festival
Ashland Independent Film Festival
Sonoma Valley Film Festival
Maryland Film Festival
Santa Cruz Film Festival
Newport Beach Film Festival
Mendocino Film Festival
Chesapeake Film Festival            
            ]]></html>
		</subsection>
	</screenings>
	
	
	<contact>
		<subsection>
			<tabName>CONTACT INFO</tabName>
			<html><![CDATA[PBS Station Relations:
Cynthia Zeiden
415.864.6305
zeidenmedia@aol.com

Intenational Distribution:
PBS International
10 Guest Street
Boston, MA 02135 USA
617.208.0735
Tom Koch: jtkoch@pbs.org
www.pbsinternational.org

Lantern Films
224 3rd Ave.
San Francisco, CA 94118

Luke Wolbach
luke@lanternfilms.com

Bill Wolbach
bill@lanternfilms.com
            ]]></html>
		</subsection>
	</contact>
    
	<buy>
		<subsection>
			<tabName>BUY THE DVD</tabName>
			<html><![CDATA[COMING SOON:

The <i>Row Hard No Excuses</i> feature length DVD, with over 35 minutes of bonus material, will be available for purchase here in May 2010.

We also plan to make it available at AMAZON, NETFLIX AND iTUNES.

Stay tuned.
            ]]></html>
		</subsection>
	</buy>	
    
</data>